const powerpoint_questions = [
  {
    question: "What file extension is used for PowerPoint presentations?",
    options: ["*.pptx", "*.ppt", "*.pps", "*.potx"],
    answer: "*.pptx",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which view in PowerPoint allows you to see multiple slides at once?",
    options: [
      "Normal View",
      "Slide Show View",
      "Slide Sorter View",
      "Outline View",
    ],
    answer: "Slide Sorter View",
  },
  //   {
  //     question: "What is the purpose of 'Design ribbon' feature in PowerPoint?",
  //     options: [
  //       "To create animations",
  //       "To suggest design layouts for slides",
  //       "To insert charts and graphs",
  //       "To spell check the presentation",
  //     ],
  //     answer: "To suggest design layouts for slides",
  //   },
  // {
  //     "question": "Which feature in PowerPoint allows you to rehearse your presentation timings?",
  //     "options": ["Presenter View", "Slide Sorter View", "Record Slide Show", "Speaker Notes"],
  //     "answer": "Record Slide Show"
  // },
  {
    question: "What is the function of the 'Transitions' tab in PowerPoint?",
    options: [
      "To insert audio files",
      "To add comments to slides",
      "To insert hyperlinks",
      "To apply animation effects between slides",
    ],
    answer: "To apply animation effects between slides",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which feature in PowerPoint allows you to record narration for your presentation?",
    options: [
      "Record Slide Show",
      "Presenter View",
      "Speaker Notes",
      "Slide Show View",
    ],
    answer: "Record Slide Show",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of 'Slide Master' in PowerPoint?",
    options: [
      "To add animations to slides",
      "To insert audio files",
      "To set the overall layout and formatting of slides",
      "To create hyperlinks",
    ],
    answer: "To set the overall layout and formatting of slides",
  },
//   {
//     question:
//       "Which option allows you to print handouts with multiple slides per page?",
//     options: [
//       "Handout Master",
//       "Presenter View",
//       "Slide Sorter View",
//       "Outline View",
//     ],
//     answer: "Handout Master",
//   },
  {
    question: "What is the purpose of 'Animation Pane' in PowerPoint?",
    options: [
      "To insert videos into slides",
      "To apply design templates",
      "To record narration",
      "To control the timing and order of animations",
    ],
    answer: "To control the timing and order of animations",
  },
  // {
  //     "question": "Which option in PowerPoint allows you to embed fonts in your presentation?",
  //     "options": ["Save As", "Slide Master", "Design Ideas", "Custom Animation"],
  //     "answer": "Save As"
  // },
  {
    question: "What is the default slide layout in PowerPoint?",
    options: ["Title and Content", "Two Content", "Blank", "Title Slide"],
    answer: "Title Slide",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which ribbon in PowerPoint allows you to add motion paths to objects?",
    options: ["Insert", "Design ", "Transitions", "Animation"],
    answer: "Animation",
  },
  {
    question: "What does the 'Rehearse Timings' option in PowerPoint do?",
    options: [
      "Records the time spent on each slide",
      "Checks for spelling errors",
      "Adds animation effects to slides",
      "Records narration",
    ],
    answer: "Records the time spent on each slide",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which view in PowerPoint allows you to see the structure of your presentation?",
    options: [
      "Normal View",
      "Outline View",
      "Slide Sorter View",
      "Presenter View",
    ],
    answer: "Outline View",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the function of 'Slide Show' tab in PowerPoint?",
    options: [
      "To apply design templates",
      "To insert audio files",
      "To start the presentation",
      "To add comments to slides",
    ],
    answer: "To start the presentation",
  },
  {
    question: "What does 'Slide Transition' in PowerPoint refer to?",
    options: [
      "The animation of text on a slide",
      "The movement between slides",
      "The transition between PowerPoint versions",
      "The addition of a new slide",
    ],
    answer: "The movement between slides",
  },
  {
    question: "Which of the following is NOT a PowerPoint animation effect?",
    options: ["Fade", "Spin", "Flip", "Zoom"],
    answer: "Flip",
  },
  // {
  //     "question": "Which feature in PowerPoint allows you to create custom animations?",
  //     "options": ["Custom Animation", "Design Ideas", "Transitions", "Animation Pane"],
  //     "answer": "Custom Animation"
  // },
  {
    question: "Which is the purpose of 'Presenter View' in PowerPoint?",
    options: [
      "To add animations to slides",
      "To apply design templates",
      "To insert audio files",
      "To view presenter notes while presenting",
    ],
    answer: "To view presenter notes while presenting",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which Ribbon in PowerPoint allows you to check for spelling errors?",
    options: ["Design", "Animation", "Review Tab", "Slide Sorter View"],
    answer: "Review Tab",
  },
  {
    question: "What is the function of 'SmartArt' in PowerPoint?",
    options: [
      "To apply design templates",
      "To insert audio files",
      "To create visual representations of information",
      "To add comments to slides",
    ],
    answer: "To create visual representations of information",
  },
  {
    question:
      "Which ribbon in PowerPoint allows you to insert audio or video files?",
    options: ["Insert Tab", "Design", "Transitions", "Home "],
    answer: "Insert Tab",
  },
  //   {
  //     question: "What is the purpose of 'Speaker Notes' in PowerPoint?",
  //     options: [
  //       "To add notes visible only to the presenter",
  //       "To record narration",
  //       "To apply design templates",
  //       "To insert audio files",
  //     ],
  //     answer: "To add notes visible only to the presenter",
  //   },
  {
    question: "What is the default slide orientation in PowerPoint?",
    options: ["Portrait", "Landscape", "Square", "A4"],
    answer: "Landscape",
  },
  {
    question: "Which command allows you to duplicate a slide in PowerPoint?",
    options: ["Ctrl + C", "Ctrl + D", "Ctrl + V", "Ctrl + X"],
    answer: "Ctrl + D",
  },
  {
    question:
      "What is the shortcut key to start a slideshow from the beginning in PowerPoint?",
    options: ["F7", "F5", "F9", "F12"],
    answer: "F5",
  },
];
